Guide to the Abe Fortas Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Supreme Court Papers, 1946-1970; Series I
  - Supreme Court October Term 1968
    - Case Files
      - No. 366 U.S. v. Covington (Box 84, Folder 1749)
      - No. 370 Golden v. Zwickler (Box 84, Folder 1750)
      - No. 376 Dunbar-Stanley Studios, Inc. v. Alabama (Box 85, Folder 1751)
      - No. 379 International Terminal Operating Co. v. N.V. Nederl. Amerik Stoomv. Maats. (Box 85, Folder 1752)
      - No. 403 McKart v. U.S. (Box 85, Folder 1753)
      - Nos. 413, 418 North Carolina v. Pearce (Box 85, Folder 1754)
      - No. 436 Rodrigue v. Aetna Casualty and Surety Co. (Box 85, Folder 1755)
      - No. 453 Gregg v. U.S. (Box 85, Folder 1756)
      - No. 463 National Labor Relations Board v. Wyman-Gordon Co. (Box 85, Folder 1757 - 1762)
      - No. 477 U.S. v. U.S. Coin and Currency (Box 85, Folder 1763)
      - No. 488 Daniel v. Paul (Box 85, Folder 1764)
      - No. 492 Bradenburg v. Ohio (Box 85, Folder 1765 - 1767)
      - No. 517 National Board of Young Men's Christian Association v. U.S. (Box 85, Folder 1768)
      - Nos. 528, 663 Nacirema Operating Co. v. Johnson (Box 86, Folder 1769 - 1772)
      - Nos. 543, 544 Williams v. Rhodes (Box 86, Folder 1773 - 1776)
      - No. 548 Jenkins v. McKeithen (Box 86, Folder 1777)
      - No. 572 Clark v. Gabriel (Box 86, Folder 1778)
      - Nos. 573, 691, 585 National Labor Relations Board v. Gissel Packing Co. (Box 86, Folder 1779)
      - No. 574 U.S. v. Estate of Grace (Box 86, Folder 1780)
      - Nos. 580, 813 Samuels v. Mackell (Box 86, Folder 1781)
      - No. 610 Sullivan v. U.S. (Box 86, Folder 1782)
      - No. 620 Moore v. Ogilvie (Box 86, Folder 1783)
      - No. 622 Maxwell v. Bishop (Box 86, Folder 1784 - 1785)
      - No. 624 Perkins v. Standard Oil Co. of California (Box 86, Folder 1786)
      - No. 641 Orozco v. Texas (Box 86, Folder 1787)
      - No. 642 Boykin v. Alabama (Box 87, Folder 1788)
      - No. 643 Frazier v. Cupp (Box 87, Folder 1789)
      - No. 644 Boulden v. Holman (Box 87, Folder 1790)
      - No. 645 Davis v. Mississippi (Box 87, Folder 1791)
      - No. 646 O'Callahan v. Parker (Box 87, Folder 1792)
      - No. 647 Hadnott v. Amos (Box 87, Folder 1793 - 1794)
      - No. 670 Banks v. California (Box 87, Folder 1795)
      - No. 672 U.S. v. King (Box 87, Folder 1796)
      - No. 701 Gaston County, North Carolina v. U.S. (Box 87, Folder 1797)
      - No. 705 Cipriano v. City of Houma (Box 87, Folder 1798)
      - No. 748 Jenkins v. Delaware (Box 87, Folder 1799)
      - No. 749 Rodriquez v. U.S. (Box 87, Folder 1800)
      - No. 750 Harrington v. California (Box 87, Folder 1801)
      - No. 770 Chimel v. California (Box 87, Folder 1802)
      - No. 776 Utah Public Service Commission v. El Paso Natural Gas Co. (Box 87, Folder 1803)
      - No. 791 Crane v. Cedar Rapids & Iowa City Railway Co. (Box 87, Folder 1804)
      - No. 798 U.S. v. Montgomery County Board of Education (Box 87, Folder 1805)
      - No. 814 DuVernay v. U.S. (Box 87, Folder 1806)
      - No. 830 Noyd v. Bond (Box 87, Folder 1807)
      - No. 841 Williams v. City of Oklahoma (Box 87, Folder 1808)
      - No. 901 Barker v. Hardway (Box 87, Folder 1809)
      - No. 983 Hanna v. U.S. (Box 87, Folder 1810)
      - No. 1070 Balistrieri v. U.S. (Box 87, Folder 1811)
      - No. 1107 Misc. Watts v. U.S. (Box 87, Folder 1812)
      - No. 1255 Misc. Bokulvich v. Jury Commission of Greene County, Alabama (Box 88, Folder 1813)
    - Library check-out list, [1968?] (Box 88, Folder 1814)
    - Memorabilia and photographs [from Supreme Court chamber?], [1965?-1969?] (Box 88, Folder 1815)
    - Poetry on cases before the Supreme Court, [1965?- 1969?] (Box 88, Folder 1816)
    - United States Court of Appeals for the First Circuit, 1966-1967 (Box 88, Folder 1817)
    - Unsolicited correspondence on Supreme Court cases, 1965-1968 (Box 88, Folder 1818)
    - Associate Justice nomination
      - Correspondence, 1965-1966
        - A-F (Box 89, Folder 1819 - 1831)
        - G-M (Box 90, Folder 1832 - 1842)
        - Mc-V (Box 91, Folder 1843 - 1855)
        - W-Z (Box 92, Folder 1856 - 1858)
        - Correspondence with justices of the U.S. Supreme Court, 1965-1966 (Box 92, Folder 1859)
        - Official documents [including correspondence], 1965-1966 (Box 92, Folder 1860)
        - Unidentified, 1965-1966 (Box 92, Folder 1861)
      - Printed materials [including newspaper clippings], 1965-1966 (Box 92, Folder 1862 - 1866)
    - Chief justice nomination
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970
        - A-B (Box 92, Folder 1867 - 1869)
        - B-K (Box 93, Folder 1870 - 1885)
        - L-S (Box 94, Folder 1886 - 1901)
        - T-Z (Box 95, Folder 1902 - 1906)
        - Partial list of correspondents regarding chief justice nomination (Box 95, Folder 1907)
        - Formal correspondence with President Johnson and senators (Box 95, Folder 1908)
        - Correspondence with justices of the U.S. Supreme Court (Box 95, Folder 1909)
        - Unidentified (Box 95, Folder 1910)
      - Background materials, general, 1965, 1968 (Box 95, Folder 1911 - 1912)
      - Background materials and memoranda, 1946, 1960-1969 (Box 95, Folder 1913 - 1914)
      - Background materials and memoranda, 1946, 1960-1969 (Box 96, Folder 1915 - 1920)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 1921 - 1923)
      - Obscenity cases [background materials, correspondence, and memoranda] (Box 97, Folder 1924)
      - Withdrawal of chief justice nomination
        - Correspondence, A-Z (Box 97, Folder 1925 - 1944)
        - Correspondence with Supreme Court justices (Box 97, Folder 1945)
    - Associate justice resignation
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970
        - A-C (Box 97, Folder 1946 - 1953)
        - D-Q (Box 98, Folder 1954 - 1971)
        - R-Z (Box 99, Folder 1972 - 1983)
        - Formal correspondence (Box 99, Folder 1984)
        - Correspondence with justices of the U.S. Supreme Court (Box 99, Folder 1985)
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1935-1983; Series II
  The correspondence and topical files series is arranged alphabetically. Folders in this series are most often titled with the name of a person. However, the materials in these folders are not limited to correspondence to or from that person, but include materials about the person as well. In its original order, complicated by multiple, conflicting filing systems, and its own cross-reference notations, Fortas seems to have filed correspondence according to what he considered its subject, and usually not by the identity of the correspondent. Additionally, Fortas sometimes indicated that he wanted a new file started with a new name that he wrote at the top of a document, or that he circled on the document. To the greatest extent possible, these indications have been followed and this original order has been maintained. It should also be noted that there is significant correspondence in every other series of the Fortas Papers, including extensive correspondence relating to Fortas's tenure on and resignation from the Supreme Court in Series I.
  The most comprehensive files in this series document Fortas's more than fifty year relationship with William O. Douglas. This formative association lasted from Fortas's days as a student of Douglas's at the Yale Law School, to Fortas's service at the Securities and Exchange Commission where Douglas served as Chairman, to their eventual joint service on the Supreme Court of the United States, and beyond. Also noteworthy are the files that are devoted to members of Fortas's extended family, such as his cousin, Meyer Fortes, the South African born social anthropologist, as well as the Aggers, the Blooms, the Kerbels, and the Slomes. There are also extensive materials in this series on Lyndon B. Johnson (supplementing the White House series), as well as many files that relate to Fortas's musical life, including intimate friendships and collaborations with Pablo Casals, Alexander Schneider, and Isaac Stern.
  - Ab-Am, 1956-1981 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Acheson, David C.
    General note
    See: Rostow, Eugene V.
  - Agger, Carolyn E., 1956-1981 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    See also: Krim, Arthur and Mathilde; McNally, James W.; Phillips, Howard; Stern, Isaac and Vera; Trampler, Walter and Margaret Stark; Weisl, Edwin L.; Williams, Maggie; Y; Yale University library; Series III. Articles--"The Constitution and the Presidency"; Speeches--Law Day, Emory University; Series IV. White House--Committee on the Preservation of; Correspondence--Personal--A-C; Klaus, Ida; Johnson, Lyndon Baines--Public relations; Simpson, Charles R.; Series VI. Institute of Judicial Administration, Project on Anglo-American Administrative Law; Series VII. Fortas, Abe-Condolences on Fortas's death.
  - Agger, Donald, 1961-1965 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Agger, Eugene E., 1956-1966 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    See also: Agger, Donald; Porter, Paul A.; Series III. Speeches--A Perspective of Labor-Management Relations, Rutgers Labor Institute; Invitations to speak, 1946-1947; Ethical Responsibilities of Government, Rutgers University; Series IV. Agger, Eugene E.
  - Albert, Carl
    See: Presidential impoundment of funds
  - Aldrich, Bailey
    See: Puerto Rico; Series III. Speeches--[No title], Judicial Conference of the First Circuit, 1968; [No title], Judicial Conference of the First Circuit, 1969; Series VI. Judicial Conference of the United States, Advisory Committee on Appellate Rules.
  - Allard, Jean
    See: Series VI. University of Chicago, School of Law.
  - Alschuler, Martha F., 1967-1969 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1975-1976 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - American Arbitration Association, 1982 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - American-Israel Cultural Foundation, 1977-1982 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    See also: Mac-Ma; Stern, Isaac and Vera.
  - American Jewish Congress
    See: Mac-Ma; Resignation, letters of; Series IV. American Jewish Congress.
  - American University. Washington College of Law, 1967-1968 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - An-Ax, 1956-1981 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - An die Musik, 1978-1980 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Applications for admission to courts, 1941-1980 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Arnold, Thurman Wesley, 1947-1981 (Box 100, Folder 13 - 14)
    See also: Pollak, Louis H.; Porter, Paul A.; Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience; Correspondence (personal)--A-C; Articles--"Outside the Law"; "The Washington Lawyer," by Charles A. Horsky; Lawyers and Social Revolutions; "Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Speeches--[No title], Convocation, Jewish Theological Seminary, 1965; In Memoriam: Louis Eisenstein; [No title], American College of Trial Lawyers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1968; Series IV. Arnold, Thurman Wesley.
  - Ashmore, Harry S.
    See: Douglas, William O., "Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom."
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1977-1981 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Aspen Music Festival
    See: Charitable contributions; Had-Hart; Hummel, Jerri Roberts Shafer; Music.
  - Aspin, Les
    See: Charitable contributions.
  - Autographs, requests for, 1967-1983 (Box 100, Folder 16 - 17)
  - Ba, 1957-1982 (Box 101, Folder 18)
  - Babb, Jervis J.
    See: Lever Brothers.
  - Baker, Robert ("Bobby") G., 1963-1979 (Box 101, Folder 19)
    See also: Series IV. Baker, Robert ("Bobby") G.
  - Balaban, Barney
    See: Johnson, Lyndon Baines.
  - Ball, George W.
    See: Maggin, Donald L.; Series IV. Arnold, Thurman Wesley.
  - Ball, Joseph A.
    See: Ba; Cooper, Evelyn N.; Porter, Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor; Series III. Speeches--[No title], Constitutional Rights Foundation; [No title], University of Southern California, 1968; [No title], American College of Trial Lawyers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1968; Series IV. Kennedy assassination, John F.
  - Banerjee, P. K., 1967-1969 (Box 101, Folder 20)
  - Barnard, Harry
    See: Douglas, William O.
  - Barness, Amnon, 1972-1974 (Box 101, Folder 21)
    See also: Sa-Sc; Series III. Speeches--[No title], Fund for Higher Education (in Israel), Los Angeles, California; Series VI. Fund for Higher Education (in Israel)
  - Bar-On, Hanan, 1978-1980 (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Bayh, Birch, 1968-1980 (Box 101, Folder 23)
    See also: charitable contributions; Series IV. State, Department of
  - Bazelon, David L., 1955-1981 (Box 101, Folder 24)
    See also: Clark, Tom C.; Douglas, William O.; Katzenbach, Nicholas deB.; Porter, Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor; Series IV. Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of; Inaugural Concert 1965; Justice, Department of; Macy, John W., Jr.; Series VI. Administrative Conference of the United States, Committee on Personnel; University of Chicago, School of Law; Washington School of Psychiatry; Judicial Conference of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, Mental disorders
  - Be, 1960-1982 (Box 101, Folder 25)
  - Bechtle, Louis C., 1971 (Box 101, Folder 26)
  - Becker, Ralph E.
    See: Johnson, Lyndon Baines; Series IV. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, John F.
  - Becker, William W.
    See: Istomin, Eugene and Marta Casals Istomin
  - Ben-Gurion, David, 1967 (Box 101, Folder 27)
  - Benítez, Jaime and family [includes photographs], 1947-1982 (Box 101, Folder 28 - 33)
    See also: Bogan, Eugene F.; Douglas, William O., memorial service; McNally, James W.; Muñoz Marín, Luis; Puerto Rico; Series IV. Dominican Republic; Series VI. President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity
  - Benton, William, 1967-1970 (Box 101, Folder 34)
  - Bentsen, Lloyd
    See: charitable contributions
  - Berkofsky, Martin
    See: Derenberg, Walter J.
  - Berle, Adolf A.
    See: Linowitz, Sol M
  - Bi-Bo, 1960-1981 (Box 102, Folder 35)
  - Black, Hugo L., 1952-1981 (Box 102, Folder 36)
    See also: Series III. Articles--"The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"; "Lyndon Johnson"
  - Blitzer, Charles
    See: Hirshhorn, Joseph H.
  - Bloch, Ernest and family, 1958-1981 (Box 102, Folder 37 - 38)
    See also: Series III. Speeches--"Lyndon Johnson," New York Times; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--A-C; Johnson, Lady Bird; 1964 Presidential campaign, contributions
  - Bloom, Esther and Israel, 1946-1982 (Box 102, Folder 39)
    See also: Series III. Speeches--Law Day, Memphis State University School of Law
  - Bloom, Julius
    See: Agger, Donald; Casals, Pablo and Marta; Grzesnikowski, Barbara and Edwin; Stern, Isaac and Vera; Series IV. Cultural activities in the White House; Series VI. Carnegie Hall Corporation and Society
  - Bloom-Gold, Raenell [includes photographs], 1957-1980 (Box 102, Folder 40)
  - Bogan, Eugene F., 1965-1981 (Box 102, Folder 41 - 46)
    See also: Douglas, William O., Douglas Anniversary Convocation; Walker, James W., Jr.; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal)--A-C; Articles--"The Constitution and the Presidency"; "The Case Against Capital Punishment"; Speeches--[No title], Talmudical Academy of Baltimore
  - Boggs, Hale
    See: Puerto Rico
  - Bone, Homer T., 1946 (Box 102, Folder 47)
  - Boorstin, Daniel J., 1956-1982 (Box 102, Folder 48)
    See also: Douglas, William O., Supreme Court of the United States, Memorial Resolutions; Istomin, Eugene and Marta Casals Istomin; Navasky, Victor S.; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal)--A-C; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal—A-C; Series VI. Kennedy Center, Performing Arts Library
  - Bork, Robert H.
    See: Warren, Earl
  - Bowles, Chester
    See: Douglas, William O.--1948 presidential campaign; Maggin, Donald L.
  - Br-By, 1956-1982 (Box 102, Folder 49)
  - Brademas, John
  - Brennan, William J., Jr., 1964-1980 (Box 102, Folder 50)
    See also: Douglas, William O.--Douglas Anniversary Convocation; Porter, Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor; Warren, Earl; Westwood, Howard C.; Series III. Speeches--The Fourteenth Amendment and Equality Under Law, New York University School of Law
  - The Brethren [by Robert Woodward and Scott Armstrong], 1979-1980 (Box 102, Folder 51)
  - Brewster, Kingman
    See: Lehner family
  - Brooks, Joseph E., 1958-1982 (Box 102, Folder 52)
  - Brown, J. Carter
    See: Scott-Grant House; Series VI. Kennedy Center
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1966-1968 (Box 102, Folder 53)
    See also: Series IV. Bundy, McGeorge; Dominican Republic
  - Burger, Warren E., [ca. 1969]-1980 (Box 102, Folder 54)
    See also: Freund Report (Study Group on the Caseload of the Supreme Court); McGuire, Rebekah L.; Porter, Paul A.; Warren, Earl; Series VI. Judicial Conference of the United States, Advisory Committee on Appellate Rules; Judicial Conference of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, Committee on Abolishment of Mandatory Capital punishment; Juvenile courts; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"
  - Burson, Harold and family [includes photographs], 1955-1982 (Box 103, Folder 55 - 57)
    See also: Benítez, Jaime and family; Johnson, Lyndon Baines, LBJ Library; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), A-C; Speeches--[No title], Hackley School, Tarrytown, New York; "Lyndon Johnson," New York Times; Series IV. Inaugural Concert 1965; 1964 Presidential campaign, contributions; 1964 Presidential campaign, groups for LBJ
  - Ca [includes photograph], 1958-1980 (Box 103, Folder 58)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1958-1962 (Box 103, Folder 59)
  - Califano, Joseph A., Jr., 1967-1969 (Box 103, Folder 60)
  - Cancio, Hiram R.
  - Canfield, Cass
    See: Douglas, William O.-- Of Men and Mountains
  - Capers, Gerald M., 1961-1981 (Box 103, Folder 61)
    See also: Southwestern College at Memphis; Series III. Speeches--Democracy in Retreat: Elephants and Elephantism, Tulane University; The Chance and the Challenge, Southwestern College at Memphis
  - Carnegie Hall Corporation and Society
    See: Stern, Isaac and Vera; Series VI. Carnegie Hall Corporation and Society
  - Carter, Rosalyn
    See: Ca; Casals, Pablo and Marta
  - Casals, Pablo and Marta
    See also: Gl-Gu; Istomin, Eugene and Marta Casals Istomin; Kennedy, Jacqueline; Montoni, Raymond; Muñoz Marín, Luis; Schneider, Alexander; Series III. Speeches--An Appreciation: 1968 Freedom House Award to Pablo Casals; Series IV. Kennedy, Jacqueline; Series VI. Kennedy Center
    - February 1958-January 1975 (Box 103, Folder 62 - 69)
    - February 1975-February 1982 (Box 104, Folder 70 - 71)
  - Ce-Ch, 1956-1982 (Box 104, Folder 72)
  - Celler, Emanuel
    See: Series VI. American Red Magen David for Israel; Judicial Conference of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, Committee on Abolishment of Mandatory Capital punishment
  - Center for Public Resources, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 73)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions
    See: Ashmore, Harry S.; Hutchins, Robert M.; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal)-- S-U; Series IV. Douglas, William O.
  - Chalk, Daphne Crampton, 1972-1978 (Box 104, Folder 74)
  - Charitable contributions, 1973-1982 (Box 104, Folder 75 - 77)
  - Charleston Conservatory of Music & Fine Arts
    See: Pittman, Roy Labon
  - Christmas gift lists, 1957-1973 (Box 104, Folder 78 - 79)
  - Cl-Con, 1956-1981 (Box 104, Folder 80)
  - Clark, Charles E.
    See: Rodell, Fred; Rogers, William D.; Yale Law School; Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--A-C
  - Clark, Elias
    See: Rodell, Fred
  - Clark, Ramsey, 1966-1978 (Box 104, Folder 81)
    See also: Puerto Rico; Series III. Speeches--[No title], Federal Bar Association, 1965
  - Clark, Samuel O., Jr.
    See: Agger, Carolyn E.; Applications for admission to courts
  - Clark, Tom C., 1956-1977 (Box 104, Folder 82)
    See also: Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. Clark, Tom C.
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1971-1973 (Box 104, Folder 83)
  - Clifford, Clark M., 1966-1969 (Box 104, Folder 84)
    See also: Douglas, William O.; Douglas, William O.--"Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom"; Porter, Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor; Series IV. Clifford, Clark M.
  - Cohen, Manuel F., 1977-1978 (Box 104, Folder 85)
  - Cohen, Sheldon S.[includes photographs], 1962-1967 (Box 105, Folder 86)
    See also: Agger, Carolyn E.; Douglas, William O.; Warren, Earl; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. Correspondence (Personal)--A-C; Johnson, Lyndon Baines--Correspondence-- Political; Niarchos, Stavros; Simpson, Charles R.
  - Colbert, Abe Fortas [includes photograph], 1974 (Box 105, Folder 87)
  - Coleman, William T., Jr.
    See: Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton & Garrison
  - Collen, Sheldon O.
    See: Friedman & Koven, personal correspondence
  - Colón, Rafael Hernández
    See: Casals, Pablo and Marta; Series III. Articles--[No title; President Reagan and the Caribbean Basin Initiative]
  - Colorado Music Festival, 1980-1981 (Box 105, Folder 88)
    See also: He-Hi
  - Congress, United States, 1974-1981 (Box 105, Folder 89)
  - Constitutional Rights Foundation, 1977-1980 (Box 105, Folder 90)
    See also: Ba
  - Conwill, Allan F.
    See: Graham, Fred P.; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience -- Correspondence (personal), A-C
  - Coo-Cu, 1956-1981 (Box 105, Folder 91)
  - Cooper, Evelyn N., 1967-1969 (Box 105, Folder 92)
    See also: Series IV. President's Council of Economic Advisers
  - Corcoran, Thomas G.
    See: Coo-Cu; Durr, Clifford J.; Stern, Isaac and Vera
  - Cottone, Benedict P., 1975 (Box 105, Folder 93)
  - Countryman, Vern
    See: Douglas, William O.--"Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom"
  - Cousins, Norman, 1965-1967 (Box 105, Folder 94)
  - Cox, Holly A., 1977-1982 (Box 105, Folder 95)
  - Cox, Hugh Baker, 1974 (Box 105, Folder 96)
  - Crocker, Thomas [with partial transcript of interview], 1967 (Box 105, Folder 97)
  - Cutler, Lloyd N.
    See: charitable contributions; Cohen, Manuel F.; Cooper, Evelyn N.
  - D, 1956-1981, undated (Box 105, Folder 98)
  - Daley, Richard J.
    See: Douglas, William O.--1948 presidential campaign
  - Davidson, C. Girard
    See: Douglas, William O.--1948 presidential campaign; Series IV. Inaugural Concert 1965
  - Davidson, Joan
    See: Douglas, William O.--Memorial service; Kaplan, J. M. and family; Series IV. Johnson, Lyndon Baines--Public relations
  - Davis, True, 1966-1968 (Box 105, Folder 99)
  - Dean, John W., III
    See: Johnson, Lyndon Baines
  - de Baat, M. G., 1951-1982 (Box 105, Folder 100 - 102)
    See also: Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton & Garrison
  - Debs, Richard
    See: Stern, Isaac and Vera
  - Ferré, Luis A., 1960-1981 (Box 105, Folder 103)
    See also: Series IV. Stevens, Roger L.
  - Derenberg, Walter J., 1974-1976 (Box 105, Folder 104)
  - Diamond, Norman
    See: D; Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--D-G; Series VI. President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity
  - Dillingham, Eve and Frank
    See: Harlan, John Marshall
  - District of Columbia Bar examination, 1945 (Box 105, Folder 105)
  - Douglas, Cathleen H.
    See: Douglas, William O.; Douglas, William O.--Douglas Anniversary Convocation, "Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom," Memorial service; Gideon, Clarence Earl; Series III. Articles-- Go East Young Man: The Early Years, by William O. Douglas
  - Douglas, William O.